

J. ALFREDO LÓPEZ GARCÍA

PERSONAL PROFILE

My name is Alfredo Lopez Garcia, I am an Engineer focused on analytics, quality processing, and hypothesis testing.

My experience is based on quality results, catalog management and processing time in order to avoid delays. As well, risks and business opportunities identification. Further, I had experience working with food companies preserving the stock quality, and taking care of distribution logistics for perishable products from the USA to retail companies in Mexico.

SKILLS

Linux, HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Python, Git, MySQL, MongoDB, Statistics, Django, Problem solving, Critical thinking.

LENGUAGES

Spanish - Native English - Advance

CONTACTO

- ialfredo.lopez.17@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/Jalfredolopez
- **687-191-9144**

EDUCATION

BEDU

FULLSTACK PYTHON | April - October 2021

• Relevant Coursework: Data visualization, Data Analytics, Data wrangling, Databases.

CENTRO DE INVESTIGACIÓN EN ALIMENTACIÓN Y DESARROLLO

Master in Science. | August 2015 - May 2017

• Relevant Coursework: Statistics, Biostatistics, Biophysics, Biochemestry.

INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE SONORA

Biotechnology engineer | August 2010 - May 2014

• Relevant Coursework: Mathematics, Physics, Statistics.

EXPERIENCE

ANALYTIC (LABORATORY TECHNICIAN)

Kimberly-Clark AFC | June 2018- March 2020

- $\bullet \quad \text{Quality testing and data management for raw material in order to produce a finished product.}\\$
- · Sample reading.
- Validation methods and establishing the methodology to verify new laboratory materials and de novo
 preparation.

QUALITY ASSURANCE

Vidimport | October 2017- May 2018

- Inventory management of products in warehouse and dashboard surveillance.
- Leading the inspection and audit process for products imported from the USA to Mexico.
- Coordinating the reconditioning process in order to improve the product quality based on the client requirements.
- \bullet $\,$ Reporting about the critical state of the product and warehouse conditions.

DEPARTAMENTO DE MICROBIOLOGÍA MOLECULAR, INSTITUTO DE BIOTECNOLOGÍA, UNAM.

Investigation stay | August - December 2016

- Performing Molecular biology to clone and express heterologously the enzyme Triosephosphate isomerase (TIM).
- Creating a mutagenic library of TIM by mutagenic PCR.
- Testing the enzyme activity for new variants of TIM in E. coli strain.

PRINCIPAL TRAINING

- Basic Course of Python. Mastermind online. 2020.
- Certification in Understanding English Language. Centro de Idiomas de la UAS. Guasave, Sinaloa 2010.